Today, we're putting together every video we have that focuses on the vowel and diphthong sounds of American English.
今天，我们将汇总所有关于美式英语元音和双元音发音的视频。
This is your one-stop shop.
这是你的一站式学习资源。
You'll see photos, up-close slow-motion words, valuable comparisons.
你将看到照片、特写慢动作单词、宝贵的比较。
We're going to talk a lot about word stress too because that really affects vowel and diphthong sounds.
我们还会详细讨论单词重音，因为这对元音和双元音发音有很大影响。
You're going to learn everything you need to know about these American English sounds.
你将学到关于这些美式英语发音的一切知识。
We'll start with the vowel AH like in father and UH like in butter.
我们将从像在“father”中的元音AH和像在“butter”中的元音UH开始。
And we'll see a comparison.
我们将进行比较。
AH as in father.
像在“father”中的AH。
This vowel needs a lot of jaw drop.
这个元音需要很大的下巴张开。
AH.
AH。
The tongue tip lightly touches behind the bottom front teeth and the back part of the tongue presses down a little bit.
舌尖轻轻触碰下前牙的后面，舌头的后部稍微向下压。
The lips are neutral, very relaxed.
嘴唇是中性的，非常放松。
AH.
AH。
Because the tongue presses down in the back, you can see further into the dark space in the mouth.
因为舌头在后部向下压，你可以看到嘴里的黑暗空间更深。
Let's see that by watching this vowel up close and in slow motion.
让我们通过观看这个元音的特写和慢动作来看看。
The lips are relaxed and the tongue is lowered in the back.
嘴唇放松，舌头在后部降低。
The inside of the mouth is dark.
嘴里的内部是黑暗的。
The word job.
单词“job”。
The jaw drops and the tongue presses down in the back.
下巴下垂，舌头在后部向下压。
AH.
AH。
When this vowel is in a stressed syllable, the voice will go up and come down in pitch.
当这个元音在重读音节中时，声音的音调会上升然后下降。
AH.
AH。
Job.
“Job”。
AH.
AH。
When it's in an unstressed syllable, it won't be as long and it won't have the up-down shape of the voice.
当它在非重读音节中时，它不会那么长，也不会有声音的上升-下降形状。
AH.
AH。
For example, in the word blockade.
例如，在单词“blockade”中。
AH.
AH。
Blockade.
“Blockade”。
The mouth position looks the same.
嘴巴的位置看起来是一样的。
Jaw drop, relaxed lips, and tongue pressed slightly down in the back.
下巴下垂，嘴唇放松，舌头在后部稍微向下压。
But because the pitch is flatter and the syllable is quicker, it sounds unstressed.
但因为音调更平，音节更快，所以听起来是非重读的。
AH.
AH。
Stressed AH.
重读的AH。
Job.
“Job”。
AH.
AH。
Unstressed AH.
非重读的AH。
Blockade.
“Blockade”。
AH.
AH。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Honest.
“Honest”。
AH.
AH。
Honest.
“Honest”。
Occupation.
“Occupation”。
AH.
AH。
Occupation.
“Occupation”。
Hot.
“Hot”。
AH.
AH。
Hot.
“Hot”。
Clock.
“Clock”。
AH.
AH。
Clock.
“Clock”。
October.
“October”。
AH.
AH。
October.
“October”。
Soft.
“Soft”。
AH.
AH。
Soft.
“Soft”。
The UH as in BUTTER vowel.
像在“BUTTER”中的UH元音。
This is a very relaxed sound.
这是一个非常放松的声音。
You can see UH.
你可以看到UH。
The jaw drops, but the rest of the mouth remains very neutral.
下巴下垂，但嘴巴的其余部分保持非常中性。
UH.
UH。
The tongue is relaxed.
舌头是放松的。
The back presses down just a little bit, and the tip is forward.
后部稍微向下压，舌尖向前。
UH.
UH。
Keep your face really relaxed.
保持你的脸非常放松。
Let's look at this sound up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离和慢动作观察这个声音。
A very relaxed jaw drop with relaxed lips.
非常放松的下巴下垂，嘴唇放松。
The tongue presses down just a bit in the back.
舌头在后部稍微向下压。
Here's the word STUFF.
这是单词“STUFF”。
Again, everything looks nice and relaxed.
再次，一切看起来都很放松。
The tongue presses down just a bit in the back.
舌头在后部稍微向下压。
In a stressed syllable, the vowel curves up, then down.
在重读音节中，元音曲线上升然后下降。
STUFF.
“STUFF”。
UH.
UH。
In an unstressed syllable, it's lower and flatter in pitch, and a little quieter and quicker.
在非重读音节中，音调更低更平，声音更安静更快。
UH.
UH。
The vowel is unstressed in the word UNDO.
在单词“UNDO”中，元音是非重读的。
UH.
UH。
Let's take a look at this word up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离和慢动作观察这个单词。
Easy jaw drop.
轻松的下巴下垂。
Lips and cheeks remain very relaxed.
嘴唇和脸颊保持非常放松。
Tongue presses down slightly in the back.
舌头在后部稍微向下压。
LOW.
“LOW”。
Notice, the jaw may drop a bit more for a stressed syllable.
注意，对于重读音节，下巴可能会下垂更多。
This is typical.
这是典型的。
Unstressed vowels and diphthongs are shorter, so there isn't as much time to make the full mouth position.
非重读的元音和双元音更短，所以没有足够的时间来完成整个口腔位置。
The UH vowel, stressed.
UH元音，重读。
STUFF.
“STUFF”。
UH.
UH。
The UH vowel, unstressed.
UH元音，非重读。
UNDO.
“UNDO”。
UH.
UH。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Sometimes.
“Sometimes”。
UH.
UH。
Sometimes.
“Sometimes”。
Money.
“Money”。
UH.
UH。
Money.
“Money”。
Above.
“Above”。
UH.
UH。
Above.
“Above”。
Untie.
“Untie”。
UH.
UH。
Untie.
“Untie”。
Uphill.
“Uphill”。
UH.
UH。
Uphill.
“Uphill”。
Fun.
“Fun”。
UH.
UH。
Fun.
“Fun”。
Here we have the AH and the UH vowels in profile.
这里我们有AH和UH元音的侧面图。
You can see for the AH vowel that the jaw might drop a little bit more.
你可以看到对于AH元音，下巴可能会下垂更多。
Also, the tongue position has a little bit of tension in it.
此外，舌头的位置有一点紧张。
That's because the tongue is flattened a little bit.
这是因为舌头稍微变平了一点。
In the UH vowel, the tongue is completely relaxed.
在UH元音中，舌头是完全放松的。
Now you'll see the mouth from the front alternating between the AH and the UH sounds.
现在你将看到从正面交替发出AH和UH声音的嘴巴。
Watch this subtle change in jaw drop.
观察这个微妙的下巴下垂变化。
And see if you can notice this subtle change in tongue position as well.
看看你是否能注意到舌头位置的微妙变化。
UH.
UH。
Now we'll do two other vowel sounds that I've noticed can be tricky for my students.
现在我们将讨论我注意到的对学生来说比较难的另外两个元音。
Set.
“Set”。
Sat.
“Sat”。
Let's talk about the EH like in BED vowel and the AH vowel like in BAT.
让我们谈谈像在“BED”中的EH元音和像在“BAT”中的AH元音。
We'll go over each sound in depth and then have a comparison.
我们将深入探讨每个声音，然后进行比较。
The EH as in BED vowel.
像在“BED”中的EH元音。
To make this sound, the jaw drops.
要发出这个声音，下巴下垂。
EH.
EH。
And the tongue remains forward with the tip touching lightly behind the bottom front teeth.
舌头保持向前，舌尖轻轻触碰下前牙的后面。
EH.
EH。
The mid-front part of the tongue lifts a little bit towards the roof of the mouth, while the back of the tongue feels like it stretches wide.
舌头的中前部稍微抬起，靠近上颚，而舌头的后部感觉像是向两侧伸展。
EH.
EH。
In a stressed syllable, the voice has a little curve up, then curve down.
在重读音节中，声音有一个小的上升曲线，然后下降。
EH.
EH。
It's stressed in the word SAID.
在单词“SAID”中是重读的。
Let's watch up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离和慢动作观察。
The jaw drops, the jaw is in the back of the bottom front teeth, and the middle part arches up towards the roof of the mouth.
下巴下垂，下巴在下前牙的后面，中间部分向上拱起靠近上颚。
Said.
“Said”。
EH.
EH。
Said.
“Said”。
In an unstressed syllable, the vowel is lower and flatter in pitch, as well as quieter and quicker.
在非重读音节中，元音的音调更低更平，声音更安静更快。
EH.
EH。
The vowel is unstressed in the word EMPLOY.
在单词“EMPLOY”中，元音是非重读的。
EH.
EH。
Let's take a look up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离和慢动作观察。
Relaxed jaw drop.
放松的下巴下垂。
The middle part of the tongue arches up towards the roof of the mouth.
舌头的中间部分向上拱起靠近上颚。
Here we compare the stressed EH from SAID on top with the unstressed version from EMPLOY on the bottom.
这里我们将“SAID”中的重读EH与“EMPLOY”中的非重读版本进行比较。
Notice the jaw drops more for the stressed version of this vowel.
注意，对于这个元音的重读版本，下巴下垂更多。
Because the unstressed version of the vowel is shorter, there isn't enough time to make the full jaw drop.
因为元音的非重读版本更短，没有足够的时间来完成整个下巴下垂。
EH, stressed.
EH，重读。
Said.
“Said”。
EH.
EH。
EH, unstressed.
EH，非重读。
EMPLOY.
“EMPLOY”。
EH.
EH。
Simple words.
简单单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Red.
“Red”。
EH.
EH。
Red.
“Red”。
Never.
“Never”。
EH.
EH。
Never.
“Never”。
Embrace.
“Embrace”。
EH.
EH。
Embrace.
“Embrace”。
Enter.
“Enter”。
EH.
EH。
Enter.
“Enter”。
Embody.
“Embody”。
EH.
EH。
Embody.
“Embody”。
Desk.
桌子。
EH.
EH。
Desk.
桌子。
The AA as in BAT vowel.
AA，如在BAT中的元音。
This is a sound that changes depending on the following sound.
这是一个根据后续声音变化的音。
So it can either be a pure vowel or a modified vowel.
所以它可以是一个纯元音或一个修饰元音。
We'll go over both in this video.
我们将在这个视频中讨论这两种情况。
To make the pure AA vowel, the jaw drops quite a bit.
要发出纯AA元音，下巴要大幅度下垂。
AA.
AA。
The tip of the tongue stays forward.
舌尖保持向前。
It's touching the back of the bottom front teeth.
它触碰到下前牙的后面。
AA.
AA。
The back part of the tongue stretches up.
舌头的后部向上伸展。
The tongue is wide.
舌头是宽的。
AA.
AA。
Because the tongue is high in the back and low in the front, you can see a lot of it.
因为舌头在后部高而在前部低，所以你可以看到很多舌头。
This is different from the AH as in FATHER vowel, for example, where the tongue presses down in the back and you see more dark space in the mouth.
这与AH如在FATHER中的元音不同，例如，舌头在后部向下压，你会看到嘴里更多的黑暗空间。
AA.
AA。
AW.
AW。
You can also see the corners of the mouth pull back and up a little bit.
你还可以看到嘴角稍微向后和向上拉。
AA.
AA。
Let's take a look at the pure AA vowel up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离和慢动作地看看纯AA元音。
The tongue tip is down and the back of the tongue lifts.
舌尖向下，舌头的后部抬起。
Here's the word SAT.
这是单词SAT。
The tongue position is easy to see because of the jaw drop needed for this vowel.
由于这个元音需要下巴下垂，舌头的位置很容易看到。
When AA is in a stressed syllable, the vowel will go up and come down in pitch.
当AA在重读音节中时，元音的音调会上升然后下降。
AA.
AA。
SAT.
SAT。
AA.
AA。
In an unstressed syllable, the vowel is flatter and lower in pitch, quieter.
在非重读音节中，元音更平坦，音调更低，更安静。
AA.
AA。
This vowel is unstressed in the second syllable of backtrack.
这个元音在backtrack的第二个音节中是非重读的。
Let's look up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离和慢动作地看看。
In the first stressed syllable, the jaw drops and we see the corners of the lips pull back and up for the stressed AA.
在第一个重读音节中，下巴下垂，我们看到嘴唇的角向后和向上拉以发出重读的AA。
It's less.
它更少。
Let's compare them.
让我们比较它们。
On top is the stressed AA.
上面是重读的AA。
You can see the jaw drops more.
你可以看到下巴下垂得更多。
For the unstressed AA, the corners of the lips are a little more relaxed than in the stressed version, where they pull slightly back and up.
对于非重读的AA，嘴唇的角比重读版本更放松，重读版本中它们稍微向后和向上拉。
Generally, the unstressed version of a vowel or diphthong is more relaxed and doesn't take the full mouth position.
通常，元音或双元音的非重读版本更放松，不需要完整的口腔位置。
In this case, a little less jaw drop and relaxed lips.
在这种情况下，下巴稍微少下垂，嘴唇放松。
This is because unstressed syllables are shorter, so we don't take the time to make the full position.
这是因为非重读音节更短，所以我们没有时间做出完整的位置。
At the beginning of this video, I said the AA vowel is not always a pure AA.
在这个视频的开头，我说AA元音并不总是纯AA。
This vowel changes when it's followed by a nasal consonant.
当它后面跟着鼻音辅音时，这个元音会改变。
When it's followed by the M or N sounds, the tongue relaxes in the back, making an UH sound after AA.
当它后面跟着M或N音时，舌头在后部放松，发出AA后的UH音。
AA.
AA。
It's not a pure AA sound.
这不是一个纯AA音。
Unfortunately, this change is not represented in the International Phonetic Alphabet.
不幸的是，这种变化在国际音标中没有表示。
It's still written with the same AA symbol.
它仍然用相同的AA符号书写。
So you just have to know when it's followed by M or N, it's different.
所以你只需要知道当它后面跟着M或N时，它是不同的。
We don't say maaan, AA, maaan, with a pure AA.
我们不说maaan，AA，maaan，用纯AA。
We say maaan.
我们说maaan。
Man.
Man。
AA.
AA。
Relaxing the tongue and corners of the lips before the consonant.
在辅音前放松舌头和嘴唇的角。
You can think of this UH relaxation as the UH as in butter sound or schwa sound.
你可以把这种UH放松想象成黄油中的UH音或schwa音。
Let's look up close and in slow motion at the word EXAM.
让我们近距离和慢动作地看看单词EXAM。
First, we see the familiar shape of the mouth when the AA is in a stressed syllable.
首先，我们看到AA在重读音节中的熟悉的嘴形。
Watch how the relaxation happens.
看看放松是如何发生的。
The corners of the lips relax in, the tongue will relax down in the back.
嘴唇的角放松，舌头在后部放松。
And the lips close for the M consonant.
嘴唇闭合以发出M辅音。
This relaxation of the corner of the lips and back of the tongue happens when the AA vowel is followed by the N consonant as well.
当AA元音后面跟着N辅音时，嘴唇的角和舌头的后部也会放松。
For example, the word hand.
例如，单词hand。
Hand.
Hand。
So when you see this symbol followed by this symbol or this symbol, it's no longer a pure AA.
所以当你看到这个符号后面跟着这个符号或这个符号时，它不再是纯AA。
Think of relaxing out of the vowel.
想象从元音中放松出来。
AA.
AA。
If the next sound is the NG consonant, it's a little different.
如果下一个音是NG辅音，那就有点不同。
Rather than AA, the vowel changes into A.
而不是AA，元音变成A。
It's really like the AY as in SAY diphthong.
这实际上就像SAY中的AY双元音。
First, the middle part of the tongue lifts towards the roof of the mouth, then the front part of the tongue.
首先，舌头的中部向上抬向口腔的顶部，然后是舌头的前部。
Let's watch GAING, up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离和慢动作地看看GAING。
The position for the first sound looks a lot like AA, but the part of the tongue lifting up is more forward.
第一个音的姿势看起来很像AA，但抬起的舌头部分更靠前。
GAING.
GAING。
Then the front part of the tongue arches up towards the roof of the mouth, while the tongue tip remains down.
然后舌头的前部向上拱向口腔的顶部，而舌尖保持向下。
When you see this symbol followed by this symbol, it's no longer a pure AA.
当你看到这个符号后面跟着这个符号时，它不再是纯AA。
It's more like AY.
更像AY。
GAING.
GAING。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Pure stressed AA.
纯重读AA。
Sat.
Sat。
AA.
AA。
Pure unstressed AA.
纯非重读AA。
Backtrack.
Backtrack。
AA.
AA。
AA vowel modified by M.
AA元音被M修饰。
Exam.
Exam。
AA.
AA。
AA vowel modified by N.
AA元音被N修饰。
Man.
Man。
AA.
AA。
AA vowel modified by NG.
AA元音被NG修饰。
GAING.
GAING。
A.
A。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Chapter.
Chapter。
AA.
AA。
Chapter.
Chapter。
Can.
Can。
AA.
AA。
Can.
Can。
Act.
Act。
AA.
AA。
Act.
Act。
Last.
Last。
AA.
AA。
Last.
Last。
Bank.
Bank。
AA.
AA。
Bank.
Bank。
Bypass.
Bypass。
AA.
AA。
Bypass.
Bypass。
Here you'll see the EH as in BED vowel on the left, and the AA as in BAT vowel on the right.
这里你会看到左边是EH如在BED中的元音，右边是AA如在BAT中的元音。
For the AA vowel, you can see that it's the back part of the tongue that raises up towards the roof of the mouth.
对于AA元音，你可以看到是舌头的后部向上抬向口腔的顶部。
For the EH vowel, it's the mid-front part of the tongue that is stretching up.
对于EH元音，是舌头的中前部向上伸展。
Also for the AA, you can see that the jaw drops just a little bit more.
同样对于AA，你可以看到下巴稍微多下垂一点。
So for the AA vowel, the tongue is raising here.
所以对于AA元音，舌头在这里抬起。
AA.
AA。
And for the EH vowel, the tongue is raising more here.
而对于EH元音，舌头在这里抬起更多。
EH.
EH。
AA.
AA。
EH.
EH。
When comparing the two sounds in isolation, you'll also notice that the jaw does not drop as much for the EH sound as the front part of the tongue is raising towards the roof of the mouth.
当单独比较这两个声音时，你还会注意到对于EH声音，下巴没有像前部舌头向上抬向口腔顶部时那样多下垂。
AA.
AA。
EH.
EH。
There's a difference in the lip position as well.
嘴唇的位置也有区别。
For the AA vowel, you may find that you get a more accurate sound if you lift a little bit here with the top lip.
对于AA元音，你可能会发现如果你在上唇这里稍微抬起一点，声音会更准确。
AA.
AA。
Whereas for the EH sound, the lips remain very relaxed and neutral.
而对于EH声音，嘴唇保持非常放松和中性。
EH.
EH。
Now we'll see the two alternating up close.
现在我们将近距离交替看到这两个声音。
AA.
AA。
EH.
EH。
AA.
AA。
EH.
EH。
To close, a few minimal pairs.
最后，一些最小对比对。
Bat.
Bat。
Bet.
Bet。
Capped.
Capped。
Kept.
Kept。
Jam.
Jam。
Gem.
Gem。
Tack.
Tack。
Tech.
Tech。
Rack.
Rack。
Wreck.
Wreck。
Next, we have another pair that's tricky for my students.
接下来，我们有另一个对我学生来说很难的对比。
E like in seat and I like in sit.
E如在seat中的音和I如在sit中的音。
We'll go over each sound in depth, and then I'll talk about length when it comes to vowel sounds.
我们将深入讨论每个声音，然后我会谈论元音声音的长度。
The EE as in SHE vowel.
EE如在SHE中的元音。
This vowel is common to many languages.
这个元音在许多语言中很常见。
To make it, the jaw drops just a little bit.
要发出这个音，下巴只需稍微下垂。
The tongue tip stays behind the bottom front teeth.
舌尖保持在下前牙后面。
The middle front part of the tongue arches up towards the roof of the mouth, diminishing the space between the tongue and the roof of the mouth.
舌头的中前部向上拱向口腔的顶部，减少舌头和口腔顶部之间的空间。
The corners of the lips pull a little wide.
嘴唇的角稍微向外拉。
EE.
EE。
They're not quite relaxed.
它们不完全放松。
Let's see this sound up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离和慢动作地看看这个声音。
A little jaw drop.
稍微下垂下巴。
Tongue tip down and forward, while the top front of the tongue arches towards the roof of the mouth.
舌尖向下和向前，而舌头的顶部前部向口腔顶部拱起。
The corners of the lips pull out.
嘴唇的角向外拉。
In the word PLEASE, the EE vowel is stressed.
在单词PLEASE中，EE元音是重读的。
Same position.
相同的位置。
When stressed, the vowel has the up-down shape of a stressed syllable.
当重读时，元音具有重读音节的上升-下降形状。
EE.
EE。
When unstressed, it's lower and flatter in pitch, quieter and faster.
当非重读时，音调更低更平，声音更安静更快。
EE.
EE。
This is a very common ending unstressed vowel in American English, because of all of the words that end in Y, like the word busy.
在美式英语中，这是一个非常常见的非重读结尾元音，因为有很多以Y结尾的单词，比如单词busy。
Let's see this word up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离和慢动作地看看这个单词。
Jaw drops.
下巴下垂。
Top front of tongue arches up, and the corners of the lips pull out.
舌头的顶部前部拱起，嘴唇的角向外拉。
Let's compare the stressed EE in PLEASE, on top, with the unstressed EE in busy, on the bottom.
让我们比较在PLEASE中的重读EE（上面）和在busy中的非重读EE（下面）。
The position for the unstressed EE is a little more relaxed.
非重读EE的位置更放松。
The jaw doesn't drop as much.
下巴没有那么多下垂。
A more relaxed mouth position for the unstressed version of a vowel or diphthong is very common because they are shorter, so there's less time to make the full mouth position.
元音或双元音的非重读版本的更放松的口腔位置很常见，因为它们更短，所以没有足够的时间做出完整的口腔位置。
Stressed EE.
重读EE。
Need.
Need。
EE.
EE。
Unstressed.
非重读。
Busy.
Busy。
EE.
EE。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Keep.
Keep。
EE.
EE。
Keep.
保持。
Early.
早。
EE.
EE。
Early.
早。
Police.
警察。
EE.
EE。
Police.
警察。
Coffee.
咖啡。
EE.
EE。
Coffee.
咖啡。
Meet.
见面。
EE.
EE。
Meet.
见面。
Each.
每个。
EE.
EE。
Each.
每个。
The IH as in SIT vowel.
IH 如 SIT 中的元音。
This vowel can be a challenge for non-native speakers.
对于非母语者来说，这个元音可能是一个挑战。
The tendency is to replace it with the EE vowel.
倾向是用 EE 元音替代它。
But for the IH vowel, the jaw drops more, so the tongue isn't as close to the roof of the mouth.
但对于 IH 元音，下巴要放得更低，所以舌头不会靠近上颚。
Let's study the mouth position.
让我们研究一下口腔位置。
There's a relaxed jaw drop.
下巴放松下垂。
The tip of the tongue stays forward, lightly touching the back of the bottom front teeth.
舌尖保持向前，轻轻触碰下前牙的后面。
The top front part of the tongue arches up towards the roof of the mouth.
舌头的前上部拱起朝向上颚。
Let's see this vowel up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察这个元音。
Relaxed jaw drop.
放松的下巴下垂。
Tongue tip forward.
舌尖向前。
Top front part of the tongue arches up towards the roof of the mouth.
舌头的前上部拱起朝向上颚。
This vowel is stressed in the word FIX.
这个元音在单词 FIX 中是重读的。
Same mouth position.
相同的口腔位置。
An up-down shape.
一个上下的形状。
IH.
IH。
Fix.
修理。
IH.
IH。
When it's in an unstressed syllable, it will be flatter and lower in pitch.
当它在非重读音节中时，它会更平和音调更低。
Quieter.
更安静。
IH.
IH。
It's unstressed in the word OFFICE.
在单词 OFFICE 中是非重读的。
IH.
IH。
Let's take a look.
让我们看看。
The mouth position is the same, but a little more relaxed.
口腔位置相同，但稍微放松一点。
Let's compare the stressed IH in FIX, on top, to the unstressed IH in OFFICE.
让我们比较 FIX 中的重读 IH 和 OFFICE 中的非重读 IH。
Notice that the jaw is more dropped for the stressed syllable.
注意重读音节的下巴更下垂。
For the unstressed IH, the jaw is less dropped.
对于非重读 IH，下巴下垂较少。
This is typical.
这是典型的。
Unstressed vowels are shorter, so there isn't as much time to make the full mouth position.
非重读元音较短，所以没有足够的时间来完成完整的口腔位置。
Fix.
修理。
IH.
IH。
Unstressed IH.
非重读 IH。
Office.
办公室。
IH.
IH。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Which.
哪个。
IH.
IH。
Which.
哪个。
Instead.
而不是。
IH.
IH。
Instead.
而不是。
Begin.
开始。
IH.
IH。
Begin.
开始。
Divorce.
离婚。
IH.
IH。
Divorce.
离婚。
Busy.
忙。
IH.
IH。
Busy.
忙。
Print.
打印。
IH.
IH。
Print.
打印。
Here along the Hudson River for Fleet Week, they're bringing out some old-time replica ships.
在哈德逊河沿岸的舰队周，他们带来了一些老式复制船。
Like the ones taken in this photo by my friend, Javon.
就像我朋友贾文拍的这张照片中的那些。
And this made me think about the vowels E and IH.
这让我想到了元音 E 和 IH。
Ships has the IH as in SIT vowel.
船有 IH 如 SIT 中的元音。
And Fleet, Week, both have the E as in SHE vowels.
而舰队、周都有 E 如 SHE 中的元音。
Now I just did a video on the IH vowel versus the E vowel, a comparison.
我刚刚做了一个关于 IH 元音与 E 元音的比较视频。
And I didn't talk about length at all.
我没有谈论长度。
That's because I don't think length really comes into play when we're talking about a vowel on its own.
那是因为我认为当我们单独谈论一个元音时，长度并不重要。
But since a lot of people teach length when they teach these two vowels, I thought I should talk about length.
但由于很多人在教授这两个元音时会教长度，我觉得我应该谈谈长度。
A lot of people will say that E is a long vowel and IH is a short vowel.
很多人会说 E 是长元音，而 IH 是短元音。
But I feel like vowels themselves don't have a length.
但我觉得元音本身没有长度。
To me, the length of a syllable depends on is it a stressed syllable or is it unstressed.
对我来说，音节的长度取决于它是重读音节还是非重读音节。
So if the IH vowel is in the stressed syllable of a content word, then it will be long, even though some people would call it a short vowel.
所以如果 IH 元音在内容词的重读音节中，它会很长，即使有些人会称它为短元音。
Another thing that can affect vowel length is the ending consonant.
另一个可以影响元音长度的因素是结尾的辅音。
If everything else is the same, and the ending consonant is voiced, then that vowel will be a little bit longer than if the ending consonant is unvoiced.
如果其他条件相同，结尾的辅音是浊音，那么那个元音会比结尾的辅音是清音时稍长。
So, for example, the word CAP will be a little bit shorter than the word CAB.
所以，例如，单词 CAP 会比单词 CAB 稍短。
CAP.
CAP。
CAB.
CAB。
So in looking at the E vowel and the IH vowel, in the word BEAT, an unvoiced consonant there at the end, that E vowel is short.
所以在看 E 元音和 IH 元音时，在单词 BEAT 中，结尾是清辅音，那个 E 元音是短的。
BEAT.
BEAT。
But in the word BID, the ending consonant there is voiced, so IH will be a little bit longer.
但在单词 BID 中，结尾的辅音是浊音，所以 IH 会稍长。
So don't think about the length of the vowel being tied to the vowel itself.
所以不要认为元音的长度与元音本身有关。
It's tied to the syllable and the sentence position and maybe the ending consonant.
它与音节和句子位置以及可能的结尾辅音有关。
This ship was interesting because instead of raising their sails, they had people standing where the sails would have been.
这艘船很有趣，因为他们没有升起帆，而是让人站在帆的位置。
Notice how BEAN, spelled with two E's, is actually pronounced with the IH as in SIT vowel.
注意 BEAN 这个词，虽然拼写是两个 E，但实际上是用 IH 如 SIT 中的元音发音。
Listen again.
再听一遍。
Where the sails would have been.
帆的位置。
Hey, Jovan.
嘿，贾文。
Yeah.
是的。
Nice socks.
好袜子。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Really like them.
真的很喜欢。
Thanks, that means a lot.
谢谢，这对我很重要。
Now you'll see videos that go into the details of all of the remaining vowel and diphthong sounds.
现在你会看到视频详细介绍所有剩余的元音和双元音。
Then we'll compare the mouth positions for the different sounds.
然后我们将比较不同声音的口腔位置。
The AH as in LAW vowel.
AH 如 LAW 中的元音。
This vowel sound, when pure, is quite similar to the AH as in FATHER vowel.
这个元音音，当纯正时，与 AH 如 FATHER 中的元音非常相似。
In some areas of the United States, we don't even make this sound.
在美国的一些地区，我们甚至不发这个音。
We always use the AH as in FATHER sound instead.
我们总是用 AH 如 FATHER 的音代替。
Also, when this vowel is followed by the R consonant, it changes.
此外，当这个元音后面跟着 R 辅音时，它会改变。
We'll go over that.
我们将讨论这个。
First, let's study the mouth position.
首先，让我们研究一下口腔位置。
To make this vowel, the jaw drops and the tongue shifts back.
要发这个元音，下巴下垂，舌头向后移动。
The tip of the tongue doesn't touch anything.
舌尖不接触任何东西。
The lips flare a bit.
嘴唇稍微张开。
AW.
AW。
One technique that might help you make this sound is to think of the cheeks coming in and shifting forward just a little bit.
一个可能帮助你发出这个音的技巧是想象脸颊稍微向内并向前移动。
AW.
AW。
This is a way to make it different from the AH as in FATHER vowel, where the lips and cheeks are totally relaxed.
这是使其与 AH 如 FATHER 中的元音不同的方法，后者的嘴唇和脸颊完全放松。
AW.
AW。
Let's watch up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察。
The jaw drops, the lips flare out a little bit, and the tongue pulls back.
下巴下垂，嘴唇稍微张开，舌头向后拉。
Let's compare with the AH as in FATHER vowel on top.
让我们与上面的 AH 如 FATHER 中的元音比较。
The lips are relaxed.
嘴唇放松。
In AW, the lips flare.
在 AW 中，嘴唇张开。
Also, notice how the tongue pulls back in the AW vowel.
还要注意在 AW 元音中舌头如何向后拉。
In a stressed syllable, this vowel has the up-down shape of stress.
在重读音节中，这个元音有上下的重音形状。
AW.
AW。
For example, in the word SAW.
例如，在单词 SAW 中。
Jaw drops, lips flare, tongue shifts back.
下巴下垂，嘴唇张开，舌头向后移动。
In an unstressed syllable, the voice will be lower in pitch, quieter, and flatter.
在非重读音节中，声音的音调会更低，更安静，更平。
Unstressed syllables won't be as long.
非重读音节不会那么长。
AH.
AH。
AW.
AW。
The voice is unstressed in the word ON.
在单词 ON 中声音是非重读的。
A function word.
一个功能词。
ON.
ON。
Function words are unstressed.
功能词是非重读的。
AW.
AW。
Note, this word can also be pronounced with the AH as in FATHER vowel.
注意，这个词也可以用 AH 如 FATHER 中的元音发音。
The vowel here is extremely quick, since it's in an unstressed syllable.
这里的元音非常快，因为它在非重读音节中。
The tongue tip isn't quite forward.
舌尖不完全向前。
The tongue is in position just an instant before the tongue flips up to make the N.
舌头在翻上去发 N 之前只在位置上停留一瞬间。
Let's compare the stressed AW in SAW on top with the unstressed AW in ON on the bottom.
让我们比较上面的重读 AW 在 SAW 中与下面的非重读 AW 在 ON 中。
You can see the jaw drops less, the lips are more relaxed, and the tongue doesn't shift back as much.
你可以看到下巴下垂较少，嘴唇更放松，舌头没有向后移动那么多。
So often, the unstressed version of a vowel or diphthong doesn't take the full mouth position of the stressed version.
所以通常，非重读版本的元音或双元音不会采取重读版本的完整口腔位置。
This vowel can be affected by following consonants.
这个元音可能会受到后续辅音的影响。
When the AW vowel is followed by the R consonant, the sound does change.
当 AW 元音后面跟着 R 辅音时，声音确实会改变。
The lips flare more, and the tongue pulls back more, and up a little bit.
嘴唇张开更多，舌头向后拉更多，并稍微向上。
This is because we blend the position for the R with the position for the AW, when the R follows the AW.
这是因为当 R 跟在 AW 后面时，我们将 R 的位置与 AW 的位置融合。
Instead of AW, the sound is AW.
而不是 AW，声音是 AW。
Co-or.
Co-or。
AW.
AW。
Let's look at another word.
让我们看看另一个单词。
Soar.
Soar。
AW.
AW。
Soar.
Soar。
AW.
AW。
Let's compare the pure AW with the AW followed by R in the word quarter on the bottom.
让我们比较纯 AW 与在单词 quarter 中由 R 修改的 AW。
You can see for the AW followed by R, the lips round more, and the jaw drops less.
你可以看到对于由 R 修改的 AW，嘴唇更圆，下巴下垂较少。
Because of the lips, it's hard to see the tongue, but it pulls back and up more than in a pure AW vowel above.
由于嘴唇，很难看到舌头，但它比上面的纯 AW 元音更向后和向上拉。
Pure stressed AW.
纯重读 AW。
Saw.
Saw。
AW.
AW。
Pure unstressed AW.
纯非重读 AW。
Un.
Un。
AW.
AW。
AW modified by R.
由 R 修改的 AW。
Co-or.
Co-or。
AW.
AW。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Boss.
老板。
AW.
AW。
Boss.
老板。
Long.
长。
AW.
AW。
Long.
长。
Runoff.
径流。
AW.
AW。
Runoff.
径流。
Lifelong.
终生。
AW.
AW。
Lifelong.
终生。
Login.
登录。
AW.
AW。
Login.
登录。
Wrong.
错误。
AW.
AW。
Wrong.
错误。
Daughter.
女儿。
AW.
AW。
Daughter.
女儿。
The schwa vowel sound.
中性元音音。
This vowel is always unstressed.
这个元音总是非重读的。
The mouth position is a lot like the UH as in butter vowel, but that vowel can be, and usually is, stressed.
嘴巴的位置很像黄油中的UH音，但那个元音可以是重读的，通常也是重读的。
But just like that vowel, everything in your lips, jaw, and neck should be relaxed for this sound.
但就像那个元音一样，嘴唇、下巴和脖子的一切都应该放松来发出这个音。
Just slightly drop your jaw to make this sound.
只需稍微放下下巴来发出这个音。
The trick is to keep everything else relaxed.
诀窍是保持其他一切放松。
Let's look at the vowel up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察这个元音。
It's possible to make this sound on its own with just the slightest jaw drop, but in actual words, you will likely see a bit more jaw drop, like here on the word sofa.
可以仅通过轻微的下巴下垂来发出这个音，但在实际单词中，你可能会看到更多的下巴下垂，比如在单词sofa中。
Lips relaxed.
嘴唇放松。
Cheeks relaxed.
脸颊放松。
Tongue forward and relaxed.
舌头向前并放松。
As I said, this vowel can only be in an unstressed syllable.
如我所说，这个元音只能出现在非重读音节中。
All other vowel and lifelong sounds can either be stressed or unstressed.
所有其他元音和终生音可以是重读或非重读的。
So the schwa will always be really fast and low in pitch.
所以中性元音总是非常快且音调低。
Uh.
呃。
Sofa.
沙发。
Uh.
呃。
Ability.
能力。
Uh.
呃。
The schwa goes with the syllabic consonants L, M, N, and R.
中性元音与音节辅音L、M、N和R一起使用。
That means when you have a syllable with a schwa followed by one of these consonants, you don't need to make the schwa.
这意味着当你有一个中性元音后跟这些辅音之一的音节时，你不需要发出中性元音。
It gets absorbed by the next sound.
它被下一个音吸收。
For example, the word father.
例如，单词father。
Ther.
Ther。
Just go from the TH sound right into the R sound without trying to make a separate schwa.
只需从TH音直接进入R音，而不尝试发出单独的中性元音。
Father.
父亲。
Ther.
Ther。
The schwa.
中性元音。
Always unstressed.
总是非重读。
Uh.
呃。
Sofa.
沙发。
Uh.
呃。
Ability.
能力。
Uh.
呃。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Allow.
允许。
Uh.
呃。
Allow.
允许。
Extra.
额外。
Uh.
呃。
Extra.
额外。
Data.
数据。
Uh.
呃。
Data.
数据。
Again.
再一次。
Uh.
呃。
Again.
再一次。
Visa.
签证。
Uh.
呃。
Visa.
签证。
About.
关于。
Uh.
呃。
About.
关于。
As in boo vowel.
如boo元音。
This sound is a little different from all of the other vowel sounds.
这个音与所有其他元音音有点不同。
Other vowel sounds have one mouth position.
其他元音音有一个嘴巴位置。
E, for example.
例如E。
And it's the position of the tongue, lips, and jaw that make the sound.
是舌头、嘴唇和下巴的位置发出这个音。
For this vowel, the movement into and out of the position is just as important as the position itself.
对于这个元音，进入和离开位置的运动与位置本身一样重要。
Eww.
Eww。
We'll talk about that in a second.
我们稍后会谈到这个。
First, let's take a look at the mouth position.
首先，让我们看看嘴巴位置。
To make this sound, the back part of the tongue stretches up towards the soft palate.
要发出这个音，舌头的后部向软腭伸展。
The front part of the tongue remains down, lightly touching, or just behind, the bottom front teeth.
舌头的前部保持向下，轻轻接触或刚好在下前牙后面。
I'm sure you can see the lips round a lot.
我相信你可以看到嘴唇圆得很多。
We want to begin this sound with lips that are more relaxed to move into this tighter lip position.
我们希望以更放松的嘴唇开始这个音，然后进入这个更紧的嘴唇位置。
Let's take the word DO as an example.
让我们以单词DO为例。
The lip position doesn't matter for the D sound.
嘴唇位置对D音不重要。
The lips can start moving into the position for the next sound when making the D, like in the consonant cluster.
在发D音时，嘴唇可以开始进入下一个音的位置，就像在辅音群中一样。
Drop.
掉落。
Did you see how my lips were already forming the R when I made the D?
你看到我在发D音时嘴唇已经在形成R了吗？
Drop.
掉落。
So what happens when we make the lip position for OO as an example?
那么当我们为OO音形成嘴唇位置时会发生什么？
As we make the D sound.
当我们发D音时。
Do.
做。
That's not the right sound.
那不是正确的音。
Do.
做。
To make the right American OO sound, the lips have to start out, more relaxed, and then come into this tight circle.
要发出正确的美式OO音，嘴唇必须从更放松开始，然后进入这个紧的圆圈。
This transition into position for the sound is just as important as the position itself.
进入音的位置的过渡与位置本身一样重要。
Let's see up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察。
Lips start in a bigger flare, more relaxed, before moving into the tighter circle.
嘴唇从更大的张开开始，更放松，然后进入更紧的圆圈。
Look at how much the corners of the lips come in for this sound.
看看嘴唇的角落为这个音收缩了多少。
Now let's take a look at the word DO.
现在让我们看看单词DO。
Remember, we don't want to start with the lips in a tight circle, but in a more relaxed position, so they can move into the tight circle.
记住，我们不想从紧的圆圈开始，而是从更放松的位置开始，这样它们可以进入紧的圆圈。
Then lips move from the flare into the tighter circle.
然后嘴唇从张开进入更紧的圆圈。
It might help to think of this sound as OO, starting with a more relaxed lip position.
可能有助于将这个音想象为OO，从更放松的嘴唇位置开始。
OO.
OO。
In a stressed syllable, you have an up-down shape in the voice.
在重读音节中，声音有一个上升-下降的形状。
OO.
OO。
In an unstressed syllable, the pitch will be flatter and lower, and it will be quieter and quicker.
在非重读音节中，音调会更平坦和更低，并且会更安静和更快。
OO.
OO。
The OO vowel is unstressed in the word, visual.
在单词visual中，OO元音是非重读的。
OO.
OO。
Let's take a look up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察。
Often, unstressed vowels have a more relaxed lip position.
通常，非重读元音有更放松的嘴唇位置。
Notice that, for the OO vowel, the lips do still come into a tight circle.
注意，对于OO元音，嘴唇仍然进入一个紧的圆圈。
The OO vowel stressed.
OO元音重读。
Do.
做。
OO.
OO。
The OO vowel unstressed.
OO元音非重读。
Visual.
视觉。
OO.
OO。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Blue.
蓝色。
OO.
OO。
Blue.
蓝色。
Issue.
问题。
OO.
OO。
Issue.
问题。
Suit.
西装。
OO.
OO。
Suit.
西装。
Move.
移动。
Influence.
影响。
OO.
OO。
Influence.
影响。
To.
到。
The R as in bird sound.
如鸟音中的R。
I sometimes say this is the vowel version of the R consonant.
我有时说这是R辅音的元音版本。
It's always followed by R, and there's no distinction between the sounds in American English.
它总是跟随R，并且在美式英语中没有音的区别。
This sound will always be written with two different International Phonetic Alphabet, or IPA, symbols, but will be pronounced R, just one sound.
这个音总是用两个不同的国际音标（IPA）符号书写，但会发音为R，只是一个音。
Bird.
鸟。
To make this sound, the corners of the lips come in, pushing the lips away from the face.
要发出这个音，嘴唇的角落收缩，将嘴唇推离脸部。
The middle part of the tongue lifts towards the roof of the mouth in the middle.
舌头的中部向上抬起，靠近口腔的顶部。
The front of the tongue hangs down, but it's drawn back a bit, so it's not touching anything.
舌头的前部下垂，但稍微向后拉，所以没有接触到任何东西。
As the tongue lifts in the middle, it may be close to the roof of the mouth without touching it, or it may touch the sides of the roof of the mouth, or the insides or bottom of the top teeth, here.
当舌头在中间抬起时，它可能接近口腔顶部而不接触，或者可能接触口腔顶部的两侧，或上牙的内侧或底部。
Rr.
Rr。
This, along with the R consonant, is one of the hardest sounds to make in American English.
这与R辅音一起，是美式英语中最难发出的音之一。
It's especially hard because the lip position hides the tongue position.
特别难，因为嘴唇位置隐藏了舌头位置。
Let's take a look.
让我们看看。
The front view doesn't help much either.
正面视图也没有太大帮助。
This is because the tongue goes back, but the lips flare forward.
这是因为舌头向后，但嘴唇向前张开。
Here's the word hurt.
这是单词hurt。
Watch the tongue pull back and up before coming forward for the T.
观察舌头在T音前向后和向上拉。
In a stressed syllable, the Rr vowel curves up, then down.
在重读音节中，Rr元音曲线上升，然后下降。
Hurt.
伤害。
Rr.
Rr。
In an unstressed syllable, it's lower in pitch, as well as quieter and quicker.
在非重读音节中，音调更低，同时更安静和更快。
Rr.
Rr。
The vowel is unstressed in the word research.
在单词research中，元音是非重读的。
Rr.
Rr。
Let's look at this word up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察这个单词。
The lips flare, but the jaw doesn't drop as much.
嘴唇张开，但下巴没有下垂太多。
Let's compare the stressed Rr in hurt on the top with the unstressed vowel in research on the bottom.
让我们比较上面的重读Rr在hurt中的情况与下面的非重读元音在research中的情况。
The lips flare for both, but in this case, there was much more jaw drop for the stressed version of this vowel.
嘴唇在两者中都张开，但在这种情况下，重读版本的元音下巴下垂得更多。
This is typical.
这是典型的。
Unstressed vowels are shorter, so there isn't as much time to make the full mouth position.
非重读元音更短，所以没有太多时间来形成完整的嘴巴位置。
Unstressed.
非重读。
Research.
研究。
Rr.
Rr。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Earth.
地球。
Rr.
Rr。
Earth.
地球。
Search.
搜索。
Rr.
Rr。
Search.
搜索。
Circle.
圆圈。
Rr.
Rr。
Circle.
圆圈。
Thirteen.
十三。
Rr.
Rr。
Thirteen.
十三。
Return.
返回。
Rr.
Rr。
Return.
返回。
Outburst.
爆发。
Rr.
呃。
Outburst.
爆发。
The UH as in push vowel.
像“推”中的“呃”元音。
To make this sound, the corners of the lips come in a little, so the lips flare away from the face.
发出这个声音时，嘴角稍微收拢，使嘴唇从脸上张开。
UH.
呃。
The back of the tongue lifts towards the back of the roof of the mouth.
舌头的后部抬起，靠近口腔顶部的后部。
The front of the tongue remains down, but it might be pulled slightly back, so it's not quite touching the back of the bottom front teeth.
舌头的前部保持向下，但可能会稍微向后拉，因此不会完全接触到下前牙的后部。
Let's look at this sound up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察这个声音。
The lips flare and the tongue inside the mouth is a little darker than on other vowels because the tongue is pulled back.
嘴唇张开，口腔内的舌头比其他元音稍微暗一些，因为舌头向后拉。
Here's the word took.
这是单词“took”。
The corners of the mouth come in to flare the lips.
嘴角收拢以张开嘴唇。
The back of the tongue lifts, and the front pulls back a little.
舌头的后部抬起，前部稍微向后拉。
In a stressed syllable, the vowel curves up, then down.
在重读音节中，元音先上升再下降。
Took.
took。
UH.
呃。
In an unstressed syllable, it's lower and flatter in pitch, as well as quieter and quicker.
在非重读音节中，音调更低更平，声音也更轻更快。
The vowel is unstressed in the word goodbye.
在单词“goodbye”中，元音是非重读的。
UH.
呃。
Let's look at this word up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察这个单词。
Again, the lips flare and the tongue lifts in the back, pulling back the front of the tongue.
同样，嘴唇张开，舌头在后部抬起，前部向后拉。
Let's compare the stressed version on top with the unstressed version on the bottom.
让我们比较上面的重读版本和下面的非重读版本。
Notice the lips flare a little less for the unstressed vowel, hiding the bottom teeth.
注意非重读元音时嘴唇张开得稍微少一些，遮住了下牙。
Generally, the unstressed version of a vowel or diphthong is more relaxed and doesn't take the full mouthful position.
通常，元音或双元音的非重读版本更放松，不会占据整个口腔位置。
In this case, a little less lip flare, and possibly less jaw drop.
在这种情况下，嘴唇张开得少一些，可能下巴也不那么下垂。
This is because unstressed syllables are shorter, so we don't take the time to make the full mouth position.
这是因为非重读音节更短，所以我们不会花时间做完整的口腔位置。
The stressed UH.
重读的呃。
Took.
took。
UH.
呃。
Unstressed.
非重读。
Goodbye.
goodbye。
UH.
呃。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Could.
could。
UH.
呃。
Could.
could。
Book.
book。
UH.
呃。
Book.
book。
Firewood.
firewood。
UH.
呃。
Firewood.
firewood。
Sugar.
sugar。
UH.
呃。
Sugar.
sugar。
Childhood.
childhood。
UH.
呃。
Childhood.
childhood。
Woman.
woman。
UH.
呃。
Woman.
woman。
The AY as in SAY diphthong.
像“说”中的“AY”双元音。
Diphthongs are a combination of two sounds, so they have a starting position and an ending position.
双元音是两个声音的组合，所以它们有一个起始位置和一个结束位置。
In the first position, the jaw drops and the tongue tip touches the back of the bottom front teeth.
在第一个位置，下巴下垂，舌尖接触下前牙的后部。
The top of the tongue pushes forward and lifts a bit.
舌头的顶部向前推并稍微抬起。
The second sound is the IH as in SIT vowel.
第二个声音是像“坐”中的“IH”元音。
To transition into this position, your jaw will lift as the top, front part of the tongue arches towards the roof of the mouth.
为了过渡到这个位置，下巴会抬起，舌头的前顶部向口腔顶部拱起。
Let's look at a word with this sound.
让我们看看带有这个声音的单词。
Pay.
pay。
The jaw drops and you can see a lot of tongue as the front and middle push up and forward.
下巴下垂，你可以看到很多舌头，因为前部和中部向上和向前推。
As the top, front part of the tongue arches up towards the roof of the mouth, the jaw comes up.
当舌头的前顶部向口腔顶部拱起时，下巴抬起。
Lips are relaxed for this diphthong.
这个双元音的嘴唇是放松的。
AY.
AY。
Pay.
pay。
In a stressed syllable like PAY, the AY diphthong curves up, then down.
在像“PAY”这样的重读音节中，AY双元音先上升再下降。
Pay.
pay。
AY.
AY。
In an unstressed syllable, it's lower and flatter in pitch, as well as quicker and quieter.
在非重读音节中，音调更低更平，声音也更轻更快。
AY.
AY。
The diphthong is unstressed in the word driveway.
在单词“driveway”中，双元音是非重读的。
AY.
AY。
Let's take a look at this word.
让我们看看这个单词。
Just as before, the jaw drops, and you can see a lot of tongue as the front and middle push up and forward.
就像之前一样，下巴下垂，你可以看到很多舌头，因为前部和中部向上和向前推。
Then the top, front part of the tongue arches up towards the roof of the mouth, and the jaw comes up.
然后舌头的前顶部向口腔顶部拱起，下巴抬起。
Jaw drop may be a little less when this diphthong is in an unstressed syllable, as we tend to simplify mouth movements in unstressed syllables, which are shorter.
当这个双元音在非重读音节中时，下巴下垂可能会少一些，因为我们倾向于简化非重读音节中的口腔动作，这些音节更短。
The AY diphthong, stressed.
AY双元音，重读。
Pay.
pay。
AY.
AY。
Unstressed.
非重读。
Driveway.
driveway。
AY.
AY。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Okay.
okay。
AY.
AY。
Okay.
okay。
Play.
play。
AY.
AY。
Play.
play。
Operate.
operate。
AY.
AY。
Operate.
operate。
Gain.
gain。
AY.
AY。
Gain.
gain。
Separate.
separate。
AY.
AY。
Separate.
separate。
Pain.
pain。
AY.
AY。
Pain.
pain。
The AI as in BY diphthong.
像“BY”中的“AI”双元音。
Diphthongs are a combination of two sounds, so they have a starting position and an ending position.
双元音是两个声音的组合，所以它们有一个起始位置和一个结束位置。
In the first position, the jaw is more dropped than in the second position.
在第一个位置，下巴比第二个位置更下垂。
The back of the tongue stretches up a little bit.
舌头的后部稍微向上伸展。
As the mouth moves into the second position, the jaw drops less as the front part of the tongue arches up towards the roof of the mouth.
当嘴巴移动到第二个位置时，下巴下垂得更少，舌头的前部向口腔顶部拱起。
For both the beginning and the end of this diphthong, the tongue tip touches the back of the bottom front teeth.
在这个双元音的开始和结束时，舌尖都接触下前牙的后部。
Up close and in slow motion, where you can really see the front part of the tongue arching up.
近距离慢动作观察，你可以真正看到舌头的前部拱起。
The jaw drops and the front part of the tongue stays down, with the tip touching the back of the bottom front teeth.
下巴下垂，舌头的前部保持向下，舌尖接触下前牙的后部。
Immediately, the tongue moves into the second position, the top front arching up towards the roof of the mouth.
舌头立即移动到第二个位置，前顶部向口腔顶部拱起。
As the tongue arches up, there's less jaw drop.
当舌头拱起时，下巴下垂得更少。
Here's the word HIGH.
这是单词“high”。
Front of the tongue down, then the jaw lifts as the front of the tongue arches towards the roof of the mouth.
舌头的前部向下，然后下巴抬起，舌头的前部向口腔顶部拱起。
In a stressed syllable, the AI diphthong curves up, then down.
在重读音节中，AI双元音先上升再下降。
HIGH.
high。
AI.
AI。
In an unstressed syllable, it's lower and flatter in pitch, as well as quicker and quieter.
在非重读音节中，音调更低更平，声音也更轻更快。
AI.
AI。
The diphthong is unstressed in the word IDEA.
在单词“idea”中，双元音是非重读的。
AI.
AI。
Let's take a look at this word.
让我们看看这个单词。
The jaw drops, but just a little bit less than it would in a stressed syllable.
下巴下垂，但比在重读音节中稍微少一些。
Then the tongue arches up towards the roof of the mouth before the tip goes to the roof of the mouth for the D.
然后舌头向口腔顶部拱起，舌尖在发D音时接触口腔顶部。
The AI diphthong stressed.
AI双元音，重读。
HIGH.
high。
AI.
AI。
The AI diphthong unstressed.
AI双元音，非重读。
IDEA.
idea。
AI.
AI。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Exercise.
exercise。
AI.
AI。
Exercise.
exercise。
Wine.
wine。
Eye.
eye。
Wine.
wine。
Bright.
bright。
Eye.
eye。
Bright.
bright。
Guy.
guy。
Eye.
eye。
Guy.
guy。
Allies.
allies。
Eye.
eye。
Allies.
allies。
Sky.
sky。
Eye.
eye。
Sky.
sky。
The OH as in NO diphthong.
像“NO”中的“OH”双元音。
Diphthongs are a combination of two sounds.
双元音是两个声音的组合。
They have a starting position and an ending position.
它们有一个起始位置和一个结束位置。
Tongue shifts back a little bit.
舌头稍微向后移动。
The lips may start relaxed or may start rounding right from the beginning.
嘴唇可能从一开始就放松，也可能从一开始就开始圆润。
After dropping the jaw, immediately start moving into the ending position.
下巴下垂后，立即开始移动到结束位置。
The lips round, and the back part of the tongue stretches up.
嘴唇圆润，舌头的后部向上伸展。
Focus on the movement of the jaw and the lip rounding.
关注下巴的运动和嘴唇的圆润。
Let's see this sound up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察这个声音。
Jaw drop for the first position.
下巴下垂到第一个位置。
And rounded lips for the second.
第二个位置嘴唇圆润。
The word SLOW.
单词“slow”。
Notice how the lips are not relaxed in the first position of this diphthong with the jaw drop.
注意在这个双元音的第一个位置下巴下垂时嘴唇并不放松。
They're flared, which does not affect the sound, as they prepare to round for the ending position.
它们是张开的，这并不影响声音，因为它们准备在结束位置圆润。
Rounded lips.
嘴唇圆润。
In a stressed syllable, the OH diphthong curves up, then down.
在重读音节中，OH双元音先上升再下降。
Slow.
slow。
OH.
OH。
In an unstressed syllable, it's lower and flatter in pitch, as well as quieter and quicker.
在非重读音节中，音调更低更平，声音也更轻更快。
OH.
OH。
The diphthong is unstressed in the word OK.
在单词“OK”中，双元音是非重读的。
OH.
OH。
Let's take a look at the word OK.
让我们看看单词“OK”。
The jaw drops, but not quite as much as it did on the stressed syllable of SLOW.
下巴下垂，但不如在“slow”的重读音节中那么多。
The lips begin to round for the transition into the ending position.
嘴唇开始圆润，为过渡到结束位置做准备。
The lips round, but not quite as much as for the stressed OH in SLOW.
嘴唇圆润，但不如在“slow”的重读OH中那么多。
Here we compare the first position of the stressed OH on top with the unstressed version on the bottom.
这里我们比较重读OH的第一个位置（上面）和非重读版本（下面）。
Less jaw drop for the unstressed version.
非重读版本下巴下垂得更少。
And here, the second position.
这里是第二个位置。
Jaw drop.
下巴下垂。
The lips round more than they do in the unstressed version.
嘴唇比在非重读版本中更圆润。
Generally, the unstressed version of a vowel or diphthong is more relaxed, and often doesn't take the full mouth position.
通常，元音或双元音的非重读版本更放松，通常不会占据整个口腔位置。
In this case, less jaw drop, and less lip rounding.
在这种情况下，下巴下垂得更少，嘴唇圆润得更少。
This is because we don't take as much time for unstressed syllables.
这是因为我们在非重读音节上花费的时间较少。
They're shorter.
它们更短。
So we simplify the mouth movements.
所以我们简化了口腔动作。
Stressed.
紧张。
Slow.
慢。
OH.
哦。
Unstressed.
不紧张。
OK.
好的。
OH.
哦。
Example words.
示例词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Alone.
独自。
OH.
哦。
Alone.
独自。
Tomorrow.
明天。
OH.
哦。
Tomorrow.
明天。
Home.
家。
OH.
哦。
Home.
家。
Window.
窗户。
OH.
哦。
Window.
窗户。
Phone.
电话。
OH.
哦。
Phone.
电话。
Social.
社交。
OH.
哦。
Social.
社交。
The OW as in NOW diphthong.
OW 如 NOW 的双元音。
Diphthongs are a combination of two sounds, so they have a starting position and an ending position.
双元音是两个声音的组合，所以它们有一个起始位置和一个结束位置。
To start this sound, drop the jaw.
要开始这个声音，张开下巴。
The first sound is similar to the AH as in BAT vowel.
第一个声音类似于 BAT 中的 AH 元音。
The tongue is wide and flat.
舌头宽而平。
The back stretches up a little bit.
后部稍微向上伸展。
The tongue tip touches the back of the bottom front teeth.
舌尖触碰下前牙的后面。
The upper lip might lift a little, or it will be relaxed.
上唇可能会稍微抬起，或者保持放松。
To transition into the second position, the lips round and the jaw drops less.
要过渡到第二个位置，嘴唇圆起，下巴下降得少。
The back of the tongue stretches up more.
舌头的后部伸展得更多。
This second position is considered the same as the UH as in PUSH vowel.
这个第二个位置被认为与 PUSH 中的 UH 元音相同。
But when it's a part of a diphthong, the lips round more than when it occurs as a pure vowel.
但当它是双元音的一部分时，嘴唇比作为纯元音时更圆。
Let's see this sound up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作看看这个声音。
Jaw drops.
下巴下降。
Here, the upper lip pulls a little bit.
这里，上唇稍微拉起。
The tongue lifts in the back.
舌头在后部抬起。
Now the lips come in and round as the jaw comes up.
现在嘴唇收拢并圆起，同时下巴抬起。
The word WOUND.
单词 WOUND。
The lips start in a tight circle for the W, but then open out for the first position of the diphthong, before rounding again for the second position of the diphthong.
嘴唇在 W 的时候开始是一个紧的圆圈，然后为双元音的第一个位置张开，再为双元音的第二个位置圆起。
In a stressed syllable, the OW diphthong curves up, then down.
在重读音节中，OW 双元音曲线上升，然后下降。
WOUND.
WOUND。
OW.
OW。
In an unstressed syllable, it's lower and flatter in pitch, as well as quieter and quicker.
在非重读音节中，音调更低更平，声音也更安静更快。
OW.
OW。
The diphthong is unstressed in the word SHUT DOWN.
在单词 SHUT DOWN 中，双元音是非重读的。
OW.
OW。
Let's take a look at this word.
让我们看看这个词。
Jaw drops, but notice the top lip is relaxed.
下巴下降，但注意上唇是放松的。
It doesn't pull up.
它没有拉起。
Tongue is lifted in the back.
舌头在后部抬起。
In the ending position, the lips aren't quite as rounded as they were in the stressed version of this diphthong.
在结束位置，嘴唇不像在这个双元音的重读版本中那样圆。
Here you see the jaw drop in the first position of the diphthong, stressed version on top.
这里你看到双元音的第一个位置的下巴下降，重读版本在上面。
Notice that the jaw doesn't drop as much for the unstressed diphthong.
注意非重读双元音的下巴没有下降那么多。
Here's the second position.
这是第二个位置。
The lips don't round as much for the unstressed diphthong.
非重读双元音的嘴唇没有那么圆。
They're more relaxed.
它们更放松。
Generally, the unstressed version of a vowel or diphthong is more relaxed, and often doesn't take the full mouth position.
通常，非重读版本的元音或双元音更放松，通常不需要完整的口腔位置。
In this case, less jaw drop, and less lip rounding.
在这种情况下，下巴下降得少，嘴唇圆得少。
This is because we don't take as much time with unstressed syllables.
这是因为我们在非重读音节上花费的时间不多。
They're shorter, so we simplify the mouth movements.
它们更短，所以我们简化了口腔动作。
The OW diphthong, stressed, wound.
OW 双元音，重读，wound。
OW.
OW。
Unstressed, shut down.
非重读，shut down。
OW.
OW。
Example words.
示例词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
About.
关于。
OW.
OW。
About.
关于。
Sound.
声音。
OW.
OW。
Sound.
声音。
House.
房子。
OW.
OW。
House.
房子。
Let down.
失望。
OW.
OW。
Let down.
失望。
Blackout.
停电。
OW.
OW。
Blackout.
停电。
Found.
发现。
OW.
OW。
Found.
发现。
The OY as in TOY diphthong.
OY 如 TOY 的双元音。
Diphthongs are a combination of two sounds, so they have a starting position and an ending position.
双元音是两个声音的组合，所以它们有一个起始位置和一个结束位置。
This diphthong begins with the AW as in LAW vowel.
这个双元音以 LAW 中的 AW 元音开始。
As a part of the diphthong, the lips round more than they do for the pure vowel by itself, like in the word LAW.
作为双元音的一部分，嘴唇比单独的纯元音更圆，比如在单词 LAW 中。
OY.
OY。
The tongue is lightly lifted and shifted a bit back, so the tip of the tongue is not touching anything.
舌头轻轻抬起并稍微向后移动，所以舌尖没有接触任何东西。
The ending position is the IH as in SIT vowel.
结束位置是 SIT 中的 IH 元音。
The lips relax, and the tongue comes forward.
嘴唇放松，舌头向前移动。
The tip lightly touches the back of the bottom front teeth, and the top, front part of the tongue arches up towards the roof of the mouth.
舌尖轻轻触碰下前牙的后面，舌头的前上部分向口腔顶部拱起。
This brings the jaw back up.
这使下巴抬起。
Let's look at this sound up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作看看这个声音。
At the beginning of the diphthong, the lips are rounded.
在双元音的开始，嘴唇是圆的。
The space inside the mouth is dark because the tongue has shifted back.
因为舌头向后移动，口腔内的空间是暗的。
For the second position, the corners of the lips have relaxed out, and the front, top part of the tongue reaches up towards the roof of the mouth.
在第二个位置，嘴唇的角放松，舌头的前上部分向口腔顶部拱起。
There's still some jaw drop.
仍然有一些下巴下降。
Here's the word TOY.
这是单词 TOY。
Again, lips round for the first sound, and relax for the second sound, as the tongue arches towards the roof of the mouth in the front.
再次，嘴唇为第一个声音圆起，为第二个声音放松，舌头在前部向口腔顶部拱起。
In a stressed syllable, the OY diphthong curves up, then down.
在重读音节中，OY 双元音曲线上升，然后下降。
TOY.
TOY。
OY.
OY。
In an unstressed syllable, it's lower and flatter in pitch, as well as quieter and quicker.
在非重读音节中，音调更低更平，声音也更安静更快。
OY.
OY。
The diphthong is unstressed in the word tabloid.
在单词 tabloid 中，双元音是非重读的。
OY.
OY。
Let's take a look at this word.
让我们看看这个词。
The diphthong looks the same.
双元音看起来一样。
Lips rounded for the beginning position, then relaxing out for the ending position, before the tongue tip flips up for the C.
嘴唇为开始位置圆起，然后为结束位置放松，舌尖在 C 时翻起。
But because the pitch is flatter and the syllable is quicker, it sounds unstressed.
但因为音调更平，音节更快，所以听起来是非重读的。
The OY diphthong.
OY 双元音。
Stressed.
重读。
TOY.
TOY。
OY.
OY。
Unstressed.
非重读。
Tabloid.
Tabloid。
OY.
OY。
Example words.
示例词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Oil.
油。
OY.
OY。
Oil.
油。
Coin.
硬币。
OY.
OY。
Coin.
硬币。
Joyful.
快乐。
OY.
OY。
Joyful.
快乐。
Steroid.
类固醇。
OY.
OY。
Steroid.
类固醇。
Loyal.
忠诚。
OY.
OY。
Loyal.
忠诚。
Boy.
男孩。
OY.
OY。
Boy.
男孩。
The U as in FEW diphthong.
U 如 FEW 的双元音。
Diphthongs are a combination of two sounds.
双元音是两个声音的组合。
They have a starting position and an ending position.
它们有一个起始位置和一个结束位置。
The first sound is the Y consonant.
第一个声音是 Y 辅音。
Diphthongs are normally made up of two vowel sounds.
双元音通常由两个元音声音组成。
But in this case, the Y consonant is acting as a vowel.
但在这种情况下，Y 辅音充当元音。
For example, in the word music.
例如，在单词 music 中。
The Y sound goes with the OO vowel to make a diphthong, rather than with the M consonant to make a consonant cluster.
Y 声音与 OO 元音结合形成双元音，而不是与 M 辅音结合形成辅音簇。
Music.
音乐。
To make the Y sound, the jaw drops a little bit.
要发出 Y 声音，下巴稍微下降。
The lips may be relaxed, or they may begin rounding for the ending position.
嘴唇可以放松，也可以开始为结束位置圆起。
The tongue tip is down, lightly touching the back of the bottom front teeth.
舌尖向下，轻轻触碰下前牙的后面。
The mid-front part of the tongue lifts and touches the roof of the mouth about here.
舌头的中前部分抬起并触碰口腔顶部大约在这里。
It pushes forward against the roof of the mouth before pulling away.
它向前推压口腔顶部，然后拉开。
As we move the tongue on the roof of the mouth, we close the vocal cords to get this sound.
当我们移动舌头在口腔顶部时，我们关闭声带以获得这个声音。
Which we add to the sound.
我们将其添加到声音中。
We release it the same time we release the tongue.
我们在释放舌头的同时释放它。
To transition into the next sound, we release right into the position of the OO as in BOO vowel.
要过渡到下一个声音，我们直接释放到 BOO 中的 OO 元音的位置。
The tongue tip doesn't need to move.
舌尖不需要移动。
It remains touching the back of the bottom front teeth.
它保持触碰下前牙的后面。
The back part of the tongue lifts towards the soft palate.
舌头的后部抬起靠近软腭。
The lips round.
嘴唇圆起。
Let's study a word with this sound, use.
让我们研究一个带有这个声音的单词，use。
Jaw drops just a little bit as the tongue lifts and presses forward against the roof of the mouth.
下巴稍微下降，舌头抬起并向前压在口腔顶部。
The lips flare in preparation for the rounding at the end of the diphthong.
嘴唇张开，为双元音结束时的圆起做准备。
Tongue releases, lifts in the back, and the lips round.
舌头释放，后部抬起，嘴唇圆起。
In a stressed syllable, the U diphthong curves up, then down.
在重读音节中，U 双元音曲线上升，然后下降。
Use.
Use。
U.
U。
In an unstressed syllable, it's lower and flatter in pitch.
在非重读音节中，音调更低更平。
As well as quieter and quicker.
声音也更安静更快。
U, U.
U, U。
The diphthong is unstressed in the word interview.
在单词 interview 中，双元音是非重读的。
U.
U。
Let's take a look at the word interview.
让我们看看单词 interview。
A little bit of lip rounding in the first position of the diphthong.
在双元音的第一个位置有一点嘴唇圆起。
But in the ending position, the lip rounding is subtle.
但在结束位置，嘴唇圆起是微妙的。
Not like in a stressed U diphthong.
不像在重读 U 双元音中。
Let's compare the ending position of the stressed U diphthong above with the unstressed diphthong below.
让我们比较重读 U 双元音的结束位置（上面）和非重读双元音（下面）。
In the stressed version, the lips round much more.
在重读版本中，嘴唇圆得多。
Generally, the unstressed version of a vowel or diphthong is more relaxed and doesn't take the full mouth position.
通常，非重读版本的元音或双元音更放松，不需要完整的口腔位置。
In this case, less lip rounding.
在这种情况下，嘴唇的圆度较小。
This is because we don't take as much time for unstressed syllables.
这是因为我们在非重读音节上花费的时间较少。
They're shorter.
它们更短。
So we simplify the mouth movements.
所以我们简化了嘴部动作。
U stressed.
U 重读。
Use.
使用。
U.
U。
Unstressed.
非重读。
Interview.
采访。
U.
U。
Example words.
示例词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Music.
音乐。
U.
U。
Music.
音乐。
Continue.
继续。
U.
U。
Continue.
继续。
Review.
复习。
U.
U。
Review.
复习。
Unite.
团结。
U.
U。
Unite.
团结。
Union.
联盟。
U.
U。
Union.
联盟。
Future.
未来。
U.
U。
Future.
未来。
In this video, we're going to do side-by-side comparisons of vowel and diphthong sounds that are similar.
在这个视频中，我们将并排比较相似的元音和双元音。
Seeing how similar sounds are different should help you solidify the individual sounds.
看到相似的声音如何不同应该能帮助你巩固个别的声音。
Let's get started.
让我们开始吧。
Notice how the lips are completely relaxed for AH, but the corners pull back and up for AA.
注意AH的嘴唇是完全放松的，但AA的嘴角会向后和向上拉。
AH.
AH。
AA.
AA。
Notice how there's more jaw drop for AW.
注意AW的下巴下垂得更多。
Press your tongue down in the back for this vowel.
将舌头向后压下以发出这个元音。
Ah.
Ah。
Notice how the corners of the lips pull back and up just a bit for the AA vowel.
注意AA元音的嘴角稍微向后和向上拉。
This is the word SAT.
这是单词SAT。
The lips are more relaxed for EH.
EH的嘴唇更放松。
This is the word SAID.
这是单词SAID。
Just a bit for AW.
AW稍微多一点。
Has more jaw drop.
下巴下垂更多。
The tongue arches closer to the roof of the mouth in EE.
舌头在EE中更接近口腔的顶部。
IH EE IH EE EE has more jaw drop.
IH EE IH EE EE的下巴下垂更多。
This is the word SAID in IH.
这是单词SAID中的IH。
The front part of the tongue arches closer to the roof of the mouth.
舌头的前部更接近口腔的顶部。
This is the word FIX.
这是单词FIX。
FIX SAID FIX SAID The jaw drops less for EE.
FIX SAID FIX SAID EE的下巴下垂较少。
Here, EE is in the word PLEASE.
这里，EE在单词PLEASE中。
Notice how much the jaw drops for the first sound of A.
注意A的第一个声音下巴下垂多少。
This is the word PAY.
这是单词PAY。
PAY PLEASE PAY PLEASE PLEASE The jaw drops more for the first sound of the diphthong in the word PAY, but the tongue is forward for both sounds.
PAY PLEASE PAY PLEASE PLEASE 在单词PAY中双元音的第一个声音下巴下垂更多，但舌头在两个声音中都向前。
Here, the IH vowel is in the word FIX.
这里，IH元音在单词FIX中。
The second half of the diphthong is the same sound as the IH vowel, but here, the jaw drops a little less.
双元音的后半部分与IH元音相同，但这里下巴下垂稍微少一些。
PAY FIX PAY FIX The mouth position for the EH vowel in SAID looks identical to the first half of the diphthong in PAY.
PAY FIX PAY FIX SAID中的EH元音的口型与PAY中双元音的前半部分看起来相同。
But look at the jaw for the second position of the AY diphthong.
但看看AY双元音的第二个位置的下巴。
Less jaw drop.
下巴下垂较少。
PAY SAID PAY SAID Notice how the lips and mouth are totally relaxed for the UH as in BUTTER vowel, but for the UR vowel, the lips flare and the tongue is pulled back.
PAY SAID PAY SAID 注意UH（如BUTTER中的元音）时嘴唇和嘴巴完全放松，但UR元音时嘴唇张开，舌头向后拉。
PAY SAID PAY SAID UH URRR UH URRR PAY SAID PAY SAID There's more jaw drop for the UH as in BUTTER sound, which is usually stressed, than for the SCHWA, which is always unstressed.
PAY SAID PAY SAID UH URRR UH URRR PAY SAID PAY SAID UH（如BUTTER中的元音）通常是重读的，比SCHWA（总是非重读的）下巴下垂更多。
Here, it looks like there's no jaw drop.
这里看起来没有下巴下垂。
PAY SAID PAY SAID UH URRR UH URRR PAY SAID UH The lips round much more for the OO vowel.
PAY SAID PAY SAID UH URRR UH URRR PAY SAID UH OO元音时嘴唇圆得多。
Flare them for the UH as in PUSH vowel.
UH（如PUSH中的元音）时张开它们。
UH OO UH OO The lips flare a bit for the UH as in PUSH vowel, but are totally relaxed for the UH as in BUTTER vowel.
UH OO UH OO UH（如PUSH中的元音）时嘴唇稍微张开，但UH（如BUTTER中的元音）时完全放松。
UH Remember to start your lips in a relaxed position for OO.
UH 记得在发OO时让嘴唇处于放松状态。
For the OH diphthong, the jaw drops a lot for the beginning sound.
OH双元音时，下巴在开始声音时下垂很多。
Then the lips make a tight circle for OO, and round, but not as much, for the second sound of OH.
然后嘴唇为OO做一个紧的圆圈，并为OH的第二个声音稍微圆一些。
OO OH OO OH The beginning position of OH looks a lot like the AH vowel, but the tongue pushes down in the back for the AH vowel.
OO OH OO OH OH的开始位置看起来很像AH元音，但AH元音时舌头在后面向下推。
The ending position of the OH diphthong has lip rounding, but the lips are always relaxed for the AH vowel.
OH双元音的结束位置有嘴唇圆形，但AH元音时嘴唇总是放松的。
OH AH OH AH Notice how the corners of the lips pull back for the first sound of the OW diphthong, but the lips flare for the AW vowel.
OH AH OH AH 注意OW双元音的第一个声音时嘴角向后拉，但AW元音时嘴唇张开。
The jaw drops much less and the lips flare a little for the second half of the OW diphthong.
OW双元音的后半部分下巴下垂得少，嘴唇稍微张开。
The mouth position doesn't change for the AW vowel.
AW元音时口型不变。
OW AW OW AW Now, we'll see and say all those sounds and words again, mixed up in a different order.
OW AW OW AW 现在，我们将再次看到并说出所有这些声音和单词，以不同的顺序混合。
Say them with me, in slow motion.
跟我一起慢速说。
AH AW AW AW AA SAT SAID AA AW UH UH UH SAT SAID AA AW AW EE EE I I FIX FIX SAID SAID EE EE I I PAY PAY PLEASE FIX FIX R R R U R U U OO UH UH OO OO I'm so glad you've taken the time to watch this video.
AH AW AW AW AA SAT SAID AA AW UH UH UH SAT SAID AA AW AW EE EE I I FIX FIX SAID SAID EE EE I I PAY PAY PLEASE FIX FIX R R R U R U U OO UH UH OO OO 我很高兴你花时间观看这个视频。
Really understanding the mouth positions for the sounds of American English can help you gain greater clarity in your spoken English.
真正理解美式英语的口型可以帮助你在口语中获得更大的清晰度。
We'll have another video coming out in a few weeks, a compilation of all of the consonant sounds.
几周后我们会有另一个视频发布，汇集所有的辅音。
For now, keep your learning going with this video and don't forget to subscribe with notifications.
现在，继续通过这个视频学习，不要忘记订阅并开启通知。
I love being your English teacher.
我喜欢做你的英语老师。
That's it and thanks so much for using Rachel's English.
就这样，非常感谢你使用Rachel's English。